# Himanshu Patel

B-4, Kachnar City Vijay Nagar, Jabalpur, India +91-9340027276 himanshu-patel@live.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/himanshu-patel-8a21959/

#### About Me:

I bring to the table 7 years of commercial experience as a full-stack developer, building applications in PHP/Laravel, Python/Django, Ruby-On-Rails using databases such as MySQL, pgSQL and MongoDB and integrating with various frontend JavaScript frameworks such as VUE and ReactJS.

As well as my software development skills I also have experience in DevOps which includes automating processes, application and system upgrades as well as ensuring security and pentesting. In addition to working with custom inhouse hosting setups based on VM's I also have experience with AWS, DigitalOcean, Azure, and VPS's.

A well as been able to learn quickly and work independently. I am also a team player, and believe in knowledge sharing and helping my co-workers

## **Skills**

#### **Technologies**

 Git, Ruby and RoR, Linux, Shell scripting, Python, MySQL, Laravel/PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3.

#### **Servers**

 Nginx, Apache, Puma, Unicorn, CentOS, Ubuntu

#### Cloud

AWS, Digital Ocean, VPS, S3
 Bucket, DigitalOcean Block

#### **Methodology**

Rapid development

#### **Source Control**

- GitHub, BitBucket, Travis CI
- Git hooks, and customization

## **Experience**

## August 2016 – April 2017 Build Environment SME/UST Global

- Handling issues related to Linux based OS. Patching, provisioning servers,
- Troubleshooting issues at various levels. Providing on call and email support to the clients.
- Datacenter operation Support.
- Worked as SME for deployment of WAS applications, supporting git issues and providing OS level support.

## April 2015 – July 2016 Senior Web Developer / Hitkarini Sabha

- Server deployment, environment setup & OS patching on Ubuntu, RHEL & CentOS.
- Web development of various websites of Hitkarini sabha and institutes associated (see references below)
- UI/UX designs and implementation using vanilla JS/HTML as well as various JS frameworks
- In-House ERP application support.
- Deploying applications on in-house production server.
- Development with PHP (based on Symfony and Laravel frameworks).

#### **April 2012 - May 2015**

## Lead RubyOnRails Developer / CodeKriegLLC

- Develop applications for a startup like helpdesk Ticketing system, Live Chat support, Main Website Application.
- Deployment of applications over Heroku, GitPages, AWS.
- Champion agile processes with regards to development.
- Application maintenance & server support.
- Implementing system automation and CI/CD using shell scripts, python and ruby.
- Repo: https://github.com/thedesignable/CodeKrieg

#### October 2011 - November 2012

## Application/Product Support Engineer / Kayako Infotech

- Troubleshooting and optimisation of Apache, IIS , PHP, MySQL.
- Deployment of VMware ESXi server as far of extending a testing strategy.
- Providing support to clients across the world over chat, tickets and phone.
- Application maintenance & support for proprietary product (Kayako Helpdesk) on Linux, Windows & VMware environments.
- Custom tools and scripting development using Python, RoR.

## January 2008 - September 2011

## Systems Administrator & Developer / Envirotech Gensets

- Technical support on Linux and Windows servers, ensuring high customer satisfaction in response time and solution.
- Writing shell scripts to automate inhouse processes.
- Monitoring server alerts and resolving issues.
- Application developments based on PHP (intranet applications)

## **Education**

### 2009 July

## Bachelor of Commerce I St. Aloysius College

Honored with best assignment created in PHP for computer applications minor subject module.

#### 2013 December

# Masters in Business Administration / CV Raman University

## Languages Known:

English, Hindi, Russian, German

## **Portfolio**

http://hitkarini.com - Developed websites in PHP and Laravel. Also revived the existing timesheet system, upgrading features of a legacy system and integrating new components. <a href="https://github.com/SelfiewiseSocial">https://github.com/SelfiewiseSocial</a> - The website built with laravel, a social network. <a href="https://github.com/thedesignable/CodeKrieg">https://github.com/thedesignable/CodeKrieg</a> - The codekrieg's official website, built with Ruby on Rails and addition components.

https://github.com/thedesignable /thedesignable.github.io - A github single page blog built with Jekyll

http://github.com/thedesignable/DCMA-project - DCMA complaint copyright project built on Laravel 5

http://github.com/thedesignable/JSTodo - JSTodo built with javascript components and HTML5 with CSS3

http://github.com/thedesignable/azeruspub - The blog based CMS software built with RubyOnRails

#### A Little More About Me

I am passionate about learning new technologies and skills. I am also an hobbyist photographer. I am a volunteer at local pet care hospital. I teach underprivileged kids on how to code, even if it is just building one page websites. I am an active discord community member for python and Django. I love helping people who would seek any sort of help in web development or anything related to tech.